John Blackwell







Summary

Highly motivated, dedicated software engineer with a knack for organization. Equipped with 2 years of experience building all aspects of several dynamic web applications including workflow management, design, server infrastructure, database management and client-side rendering. Seeking a role as a front end or full stack JavaScript developer.

Skills

Problem Solving, Personnel Management, Communication, Customer Service, Multi-Tasking, HTML5, CSS3, Git Control Flow, PHP, Ruby, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript (ES6) including, React and React-Native, JSON, ¡Query, Handlebars, EJS, Node, Express, API interactions, Office Suite (Word, Excel, Outlook, Access, PowerPoint, Publisher), Reserve Interactive (Events Software), Social Tables (Events Software)

Experience

RTS Labs Richmond, VA/Remote Software Engineer

July 2018 -

- Follow best practices such as test-driven development, iterative refactoring, team code and style standards
- Work with teams to analyze client needs and determine requirements and acceptable solutions for clients.
- Design, develop, test and deploy software applications
- Write clean, maintainable and efficient code
- Drive continuous adoption and integration of relevant new technologies into new designs
 - Including: styled-components, redux, react-hooks, react-native, Gatsby is, react-spring, GraphQL

Trilogy Education Remote Senior Tutor March 2018 - October 2018

- Schedule appointments for remote tutoring sessions with 50 students over the course of the job
 - Explain principles of Computer Science, JavaScript, and other technologies to current students
- Assist with homework and activities from the syllabus

Kinja Scraper Richmond, VA March 2018 Full Stack Developer

A web app that allows a user to scrape headlines from the Kinja CMS

- Built with the MERN stack. Uses modern React including Hooks and Styled Components
- https://github.com/jayblack388/kinja-scraper2.0

The Commonwealth Club

Richmond, VA

Banquet Manager

May 2013 – September 2017

- Find, interview, and hire new staff members for front of house positions
- Develop and implement training programs for front of house staff
- Schedule staffing for booked events on a weekly basis
- Book and plan events of varying sizes
- Oversee daily operations of banquet department
- Communicate effectively with members and staff to create a positive and cohesive environment

Education

University of Richmond

October 2017 – April 2018

University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp- JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

An intensive 24 weeklong program designed to immerse students in designing and building web applications. Skills Learned: HTML5, CSS3, Git, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 3/4, Firebase, node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, React.js